(upbeat music)
- Hello, English learners.
Welcome back to English Pot.
My name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- And today we're bringing you part four
of our romantic series
called, "I'm Sorry, I Love You.
" - Yeah, and today we've
got some drama, don't we?
- We got a lot of drama and
we got a lot of useful language.
- Yeah, we're gonna learn some
phrases we can use to describe a mistake.
And we're also going to learn
how we can comfort someone.
We can make them feel better.
- Okay, exactly.
So in our dialogue today, Veronica
and her boyfriend are on a break.
- Right.
- So what does it mean to be on a break?
- Well, it means you stop having a
romantic relationship for a short time.
- So you can say we are on a break?
- So we're not dating.
- We're not dating.
- Oh, we don't date.
- All right.
(laughing)
- And we could say, let's take a break.
- Right, so we've got the state on
a break and the action, take a break.
- Take a break.
- Okay, let's take a break.
Okay, so let's listen to our dialogue
and it's gonna be a little bit fast
and the girl I think she's crying, so it'll
be a little bit difficult to understand.
- But Marco and I will
come back in a minute
and we'll talk about some
of the difficult language here.
(upbeat music)
- So I said, let's take a break.
- And since that night,
I've been waiting for
him to call but I still
haven't heard from him.
- You don't think he's
seeing someone else, do you?
- Come on, don't be so dramatic.
I'm sure everything is
going to work out just fine.
- You think so?
- Oh no, how could he do this to me?
I'm sure he's cheating on me.
Why else would he call?
- But you two are on a break.
Theoretically, he can do whatever he likes.
He's in love with my life.
(laughing)
I really messed this up.
- Come on, hun, pull yourself together.
It's going to be all right.
(buzzer)
But I, I still love him
and it's all my fault.
I can't believe how immature
and selfish I was being.
I mean, he is a firefighter.
It's not like he can just leave someone
on the burning building
and meet me for dinner.
(laughing)
I totally messed this up.
- You know what, Veronica?
I think he should make the first step.
I'm sure he'll forgive you.
- No.
This is not going to happen, I,
I ruined everything.
- Hey, do you hear something?
- Since it's your lovely firefighter.
♪ Don't you know I sit around ♪
♪ With my head hanging down ♪
♪ And I wonder ♪
(upbeat music)
- Wow, that's a romantic
boyfriend singing in the street.
- Yeah, yeah, that's amazing.
Have you ever done that for a girl?
- No.
(laughing)
Have you ever sung to a girl at KTV?
- I've sung to a girl in KTV.
- And karaoke.
- Karaoke, yeah.
So, but not so much as an on the street
with all the neighbors coming out to see me.
- Wow, okay, well, I don't blame you.
- All right, let's take
a look at the language
that we saw in our dialogue
on language takeaway.
- Language takeaway.
- All right, so let's take
a look at our first word.
Seeing someone.
- Seeing someone.
- So if I'm seeing someone.
- You're dating them.
- I'm dating them.
- Yeah.
- I'm frequently going
out with that person.
- Right.
- So, but it's not very serious.
- No, it is serious.
- But not really.
It's one of a casual thing.
It's not very exclusive.
- So, if you are seeing someone,
then you can also see another person.
- Maybe.
- Hmm.
- Well, I think sometimes seeing someone
can mean actually they're
your boyfriend or girlfriend.
Like, I'm seeing John, he's my boyfriend.
- Okay, yeah, see,
this is the difficult thing
about seeing someone is that for
some people, it means it's really serious.
Well, for other people,
it means it's more casual.
- I guess it's important
that you and your boyfriend
or girlfriend share the same
view on the meaning of this word.
- Have to agree on what
seeing someone means.
- Okay, well, what's our next word, Marco?
- Cheating on.
- Cheating on someone.
- Cheating on me.
- Okay, so if you're cheating on someone,
- Then you are like kissing or
even having sex with someone
who's not your boyfriend or your
husband or your girlfriend or your wife.
- Exactly, so if I say she cheated on me,
that means that my girlfriend
kissed or had sex with another guy.
- Right.
- But if I say she cheated me.
- Yeah, that's different.
- That's different, right?
- It's different.
- She sold you something
for a really high price.
- She cheated me.
- Yeah.
- Or maybe she sold me
something that was fake.
- Yeah, or broken or broken.
- Or broken.
- So cheated on is really
different from cheated.
- Okay, let's take a look at our next word.
Mess this up.
- Mess this up.
So Marco, this is a phrasal verb.
And that means we can sort of
switch it around a little bit, right?
- Exactly.
Why don't we listen to some examples and
then we can come back and talk some more?
- Example one.
- I messed up on the exam
and now I won't pass my class.
- Example two.
- When I'm cooking, I always
mess up and burn the rice.
- Okay, so messed up,
it's pretty clear, I think.
- Yeah.
- All right, let's take a
look at our next word.
Imature.
- Imature.
So when someone is immature,
they're acting really young.
- Really young, right?
But it's not a very
good thing to be mature.
- No, it has a negative meaning.
- Right, it's normal for
children to be immature.
- 'Cause they're children, right?
But not an adult.
- Yes.
- Okay.
- So we've got some
examples that will help you
to understand this
word a little bit better.
- Example one.
- Your toilet jugs are not funny.
Stop being sorry, immature.
- Example two.
- Genie acts like she's 16.
She's set immature.
- Example three.
- God, you and your friends
always act so immature.
- All right, so immature.
Now let's take a look at our next word.
Selfish.
- Selfish.
- So a selfish person.
- Is a person who only
thinks about themselves?
- Okay, so I only think
about me, no one else.
- Yeah, you don't care
about other people's feelings.
- Okay.
So it's not a good thing
to be a mature or selfish.
- Exactly.
- Okay, so I think it's time for
us to listen to our dialogue again.
We're gonna slow it down a little bit.
- And this will help you to understand
these faces a little bit more clearly.
- So I said, let's take a break.
And since that night,
I've been waiting for him
to call, but I still
haven't heard from him.
You don't think he's seeing
someone else, do you?
- Come on, don't be so dramatic.
I'm sure everything is
going to work out just fine.
- You think so?
Oh no, how can he do this to me?
I'm sure he's cheating on me.
Why else wouldn't he call?
- But you two are on
a break, theoretically.
He can do whatever he likes.
- He's the love of my life.
I've really messed this up.
- Come on, Hun, pull yourself together.
It's going to be all right.
- But I still love him,
and it's all my fault.
- I can't believe how immature
and selfish I was being.
I mean, he is a firefighter.
It's not like he can just leave someone in
a burning building and meet me for dinner.
I've totally messed this up.
- You know what, Veronica?
I think you should make the first step.
I'm sure he'll forgive you.
- No, this is not going to happen.
I ruined everything.
- Hey, do you hear something?
Guess what?
It's your lovely firefighter.
(upbeat music)
- Okay, so we saw Veronica's
friend trying to calm her down.
- Yeah, trying to comfort her.
- Okay, to make her feel
better, let's take a look
at some of the phrases
she used in fluency builder.
- Fluency builder.
- Okay, so what was the
first phrase that she said?
- Everything is going
to work out just fine.
- What does that mean?
- It's going to be okay, right?
- Yeah, the problem will be solved.
- Okay, so if somebody's
worried or somebody is crying,
you can say, "Ah, don't worry,
everything is going to "work out just fine.
" Okay, okay, let's
look at the next one.
Pull yourself together.
- Pull yourself together.
- So what does that mean, exactly?
It sounds kind of weird.
- I know, I guess it just means stop
crying, relax, and take a deep breath.
- Okay, just like calm down.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Get organized with your
ideas and your thoughts.
- Yeah, so you can think of maybe somebody
who's got tears down their face,
and everything is sort of in a mess.
If you pull it together, they clean
up, and they sort of relax, right?
- Okay, pull yourself together.
- All right, and the last phrase
that we saw, it's going to be all right.
- It's going to be all right.
- So it's going to be all right,
means everything is going to be okay.
- Yeah, it's going to be fine.
- It's going to be fine.
- The problem will go away.
You'll feel better.
- Maybe you could
even say it'll be all right.
- Yeah, yeah.
- It'll be all right.
- Yeah.
- These are three really helpful phrases
that you can use when you
want to say something nice
to a friend or a colleague
who has a problem.
- Okay, exactly very useful language.
So let's listen to some more examples.
- Example one.
- Don't worry, everything's
going to work out just fine.
I'm sure he still loves you.
- Example two.
- Everything's going to be all right.
We'll find your puppy.
Don't worry.
- Oh, yeah, I'll tell you
everything you're doing.
- Okay, great examples
and I think it's clear now.
So let's listen to our dialogue again and
then we'll come back and talk some more.
(upbeat music)
So I said, let's take a
break and since that night,
I've been waiting for him to call,
but I still haven't heard from him.
- You don't think he's
seeing someone else, do you?
- Come on, don't be so dramatic.
I'm sure everything is
going to work out just fine.
- You think so?
Oh, no, how do you do this to me?
I'm sure he's cheating on me.
Why else wouldn't he call?
- But you two are on a break.
Theoretically, he can do whatever he likes.
- He's a love of my life.
- I really messed this up.
- Come on, hun, pull yourself together.
It's going to be all right.
(buzzer)
But I, I still love him
and it's all my fault.
I can't believe how immature
and selfish I was being.
I mean, he is a firefighter.
It's not like he can just leave someone in
a burning building and meet me for dinner.
I've totally messed this up.
- You know what, Veronica?
I think you should make the first step.
I'm sure he'll forgive you.
- No.
- This is not going to happen, I,
I ruined everything.
- Hey, do you hear something?
♪ Since it's a year old ♪
- That's what, it's
your lovely firefighter.
♪ Don't you know I sit around ♪
♪ With my head hangin' down ♪
♪ No wonder ♪
(gentle music)
- Okay, yeah, I really liked this dialogue.
It's so romantic.
- Yeah.
- It's drama, but at
the same time romantic.
- Mm-hmm.
- So we want to know what
you think will happen next.
- Yeah, will they get back together?
- Will they get married?
- Will they have a baby?
- Maybe they'll break up forever.
- Maybe she'll move
halfway across the world.
- Anything could happen.
So let us know what you think will happen.
- Mm-hmm.
- Come to our website
at www.englishpod.
com and leave your
comments on the lesson page.
- Exactly, and maybe you'll be right.
- Yeah.
- You never know.
- Okay, so we're out of time for today.
I hope you guys had fun
and we'll see you next time.
Until then, it's--
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
(upbeat music)